AMANDEEP SINGH DHARIWAL



Mob: 9588460429, 9071685835

Email: singh.bittu553@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE: -

With my hard work and dedication, I want to reach a position where I earn respect for my work and knowledge while making positive contribution to the organization. A highly motivated and dedicated Mechanical Engineer with 5 years' experience in New Product development, IE & Production.

Work Experience: -(1)

COMPANY: DAIKIN

Duration: 1 Aug 2022 - Present

Experience: 1 month

Title: Engineer (Manufacturing Engineering)

(CAC,RAC,VRV)

New Product development(pilot trial)

Time Study

Lean Manufacturing

Equipment & Facility installation

Kaizen

Plant and assembly line layout

Work Experience: -(2)

COMPANY: VOLTAS

Duration: 30 Sept 2021 - 21 July 2022

Experience: 10months

Title: Engineer in (Manufacturing Engineering

(CAC)

Time & Motion study.

Tools and Jigs development.

Plant and assembly line layout

Lean, Value Stream mapping

Capex Monitoring, Optimum Utilization of Capex

Identifying capital requirement, allocation and monitoring of Budget. Generating capex report.

Cost Saving in techno-commercial negotiations and optimization

Six sigma

Quality and productivity improvement by Implement Kaizen/POKAYOE

Problem solving to reduce machine downtime.

Process Improvements

Shop floor designing for better utilization of available space

Work Experience: -(2)

COMPANY: HAIER

Duration: 6 Mar 2020 - 30 Sept 2021

Experience: 1 year 6months

Title: Senior Engineer in

Production(Manufacturing & Industrial

Engineering) (AC)

Company Profile:

Multi Skilling of all operators in the dept.(R/A)

Effective utilization applicable PPEs (R/AC)

Preparation & Monitoring of EAIS, HIRA and Risk & Opportunities of work place (R/AC) Co-ordination with team during Emergency situation (R/A)

Industrial engineering (Time study, Manpower reduction, Cycle time reduction)

Identification of value added, Non-value added & waste activity, work distribution and line balancing of the assembly line by conducting time study to reduce the bottleneck points on the line.

Work Experience: -(3)

COMPANY: MAHINDRA & MAHINDRA

Duration: 5 Mar 2018 - 5 Mar 2020

Experience: 2years

Title: Process Engineer in NPD & IE(Tractor)

Company Profile:

- Handling new model (H1, H2, NOVO, P2, CRDe, MUSA, spacile requirement).
- Manage all activity (QP, PDI, Gate audit All Fitment).
- Develop documentation for New product production (e.g., PFD, FMEA, MSA, Control plan, & SOPs) For Introduction of New product at Domestic & Export market
- Working on CRE project Assembly of Tractor parts.
- Resolving Gate audit issues by root cause analysis & training to operators to improve Quality.
- Knowledge on quality tool on 7QC Tool.
- Assistance to Audit coordinator for Audits e.g. ISO/TS 9001, OHSAS, TMW, AFS, etc.
- Handling of Trials & PPAP/APQP Documentation related to Design, Facility & Process Changes.
- Responsible for shop management and alignments with departmental Parameters (e.g. Safety & quality poka yoke, kaizen culture, CIT, OIT,

innovation, cost saving - CRE, etc.)

•LEAN Manufacturing, 6s, Line improvement.

Educational Oualifications: -

- Diploma in **Mechanical** Engineering in 2017 from Advanced technical training from Shri sai polytechnic (AICTE) approved.
- 12th from Gurunanak college in 2013
- 10th from BJM Caramel Academy in 2010

Personal Particulars: -

Date of Birth : 15 Feb 1995Sex : Male.

Marital Status. : Un married
Nationality : Indian
Current CTC : 615000